Guide to the Mabel Loomis Todd Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Lectures, 1891-1931; Series IV; 6.25 linear feet (15 boxes)
  - Printed Matter
    - Providence, R.I., 1904-1908 (Box 67, Folder 439)
    - Quincy, Mass., 1899-1913 (Box 67, Folder 440)
    - Racine, Wisc., 1903 (Box 67, Folder 441)
    - Rockland, Me., 1898-1912 (Box 67, Folder 442)
    - Rocky River, Ohio, 1898 (Box 67, Folder 443)
    - Roxbury, Mass., 1898-1901 (Box 67, Folder 444)
    - Rutland, Vt., 1909 (Box 67, Folder 445)
    - St. Johnsbury, Vt., 1894 (Box 67, Folder 446)
    - Sewickley, Pa., 1901, 1915 (Box 67, Folder 447)
    - Somersworth, N.H., 1903 (Box 67, Folder 448)
    - Somerville, Mass., 1903 (Box 67, Folder 449)
    - South Hadley, Mass., 1905, 1930 (Box 67, Folder 450)
    - South Weymouth, Mass., 1900 (Box 67, Folder 451)
    - Springfield, Mass., 1891, 1897, 1901, 1910 (Box 67, Folder 452)
    - Springfield, Ohio, 1903 (Box 67, Folder 453)
    - Tacoma, Wash., 1902 (Box 67, Folder 454)
    - Troy, N.Y., 1908 (Box 67, Folder 455)
    - Turner Falls, Mass., 1905 (Box 67, Folder 456)
    - Waltham, Mass., 1903 (Box 67, Folder 457)
    - Ware, Mass., 1894 (Box 67, Folder 458)
    - Washington, D.C., 1900 (Box 67, Folder 459)
    - Waterbury, Ct., 1899, 1904 (Box 67, Folder 460)
    - Watertown, Mass., 1899 (Box 67, Folder 461)
    - West Bridgewater, Mass., 1906 (Box 67, Folder 462)
    - Westfield, Mass., 1893 (Box 67, Folder 463)
    - Weymouth, Mass., 1899, 1913 (Box 67, Folder 464)
    - Williamsburg, Mass., 1902 (Box 67, Folder 465)
    - Winchendon, Mass., 1902 (Box 67, Folder 466)
    - Winthrop, Mass., 1908 (Box 67, Folder 467)
    - Woburn, Mass., 1907 (Box 67, Folder 468)
    - Woonsocket, R.I., 1898, 1902, undated (Box 67, Folder 469)
    - Worcester, Mass., 1895, 1907-1908, 1910 (Box 67, Folder 470)
    - Wyoming, N.Y., 1891 (Box 67, Folder 471)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 67, Folder 472)
    - Unidentified, Undated (Box 67, Folder 473)
- Writings, 1881-1932; Series V; 6.25 linear feet (15 boxes)
  WRITINGS has three sections: Books, Published Articles, and Unpublished Writings. Each section is arranged chronologically. Those materials without dates are filed at the end of each section.
  - Books
    - Footprints: drafts, lists of recipients, correspondence, copies, 1883 (Box 68, Folder 1-7)
    - Emily Dickinson's Poems: drafts, reviews, correspondence, vol. I-II, 1890-1891 (Box 68, Folder 8-12)
    - Emily Dickinson's Letters: Introduction--Chapter V, 1894 (Box 68, Folder 13-18)
    - Emily Dickinson's Letters, 1894
      - Chapters VI-X (Box 69, Folder 19-24)
      - Notes, advertising, reviews (Box 69, Folder 25-27)
    - Total Eclipses of the Sun, 1894
      - Proofs (Box 69, Folder 28-29)
      - Cover (Box 69, Folder 30)
      - Illustrations (Box 69, Folder 31)
      - Publicity (Box 69, Folder 32)
      - Reviews, notices, related articles (Box 70, Folder 33-35)
      - Publishers' correspondence, contract (Box 70, Folder 36)
      - General correspondence (Box 70, Folder 37)
    - Emily Dickinson's Poems, 1896
      - Reviews, advertisements (Box 70, Folder 38)
    - A Cycle of Sonnets, 1896
      - Final draft (Box 70, Folder 39)
      - Proofs, annotated by MLT (Box 70, Folder 40)
      - Reviews, notices (Box 70, Folder 41)
      - Publishers' correspondence (Box 70, Folder 42)
      - General correspondence (Box 70, Folder 43)
    - Corona and Sunset, 1896-1924
      - Final draft (Box 70, Folder 44)
      - Index (Box 70, Folder 45)
      - Photos (Box 70, Folder 46-48)
      - Illustration (Box 70, Folder 49)
      - Cover design, notes on text and photos (Box 70, Folder 50)
      - MLT's notes (Box 70, Folder 51)
      - DPT's notes (Box 70, Folder 52)
      - Excerpts (Box 70, Folder 53)
      - Publicity (Box 70, Folder 54)
      - Reviews and notices (Box 70, Folder 55)
      - Reviews and notices (Box 71, Folder 56-59)
      - Publisher's correspondence (Box 71, Folder 60-62)
      - Correspondence (Box 71, Folder 63)
      - Letters on publication (Box 71, Folder 64-65)
      - Publisher's financial statements (Box 71, Folder 66)
    - Steel's Popular Astronomy, 1899
      - Publicity (Box 71, Folder 67)
      - Publisher's correspondence (Box 71, Folder 68)
    - A Cycle of Sunsets, 1910
      - First draft (Box 71, Folder 69)
      - Notes (Box 71, Folder 70)
      - Excerpts (Box 71, Folder 71)
      - Publicity (Box 71, Folder 72)
      - Reviews and notices (Box 71, Folder 73-75)
      - Publisher's correspondence (Box 71, Folder 76)
      - Letter on publication (Box 71, Folder 77)
    - Tripoli the Mysterious, 1912
      - Foreword (Box 72, Folder 78)
      - Table of contents, notes (Box 72, Folder 79)
      - Notes (Box 72, Folder 80)
      - Research material (Box 72, Folder 81-82)
      - Illustrations (Box 72, Folder 83)
      - Reviews and notices (Box 72, Folder 84-85)
      - Publisher's correspondence including contract (Box 72, Folder 86)
      - Letters on publication (Box 72, Folder 87)
    - Letters of Emily Dickinson, 1917, 1931, 1932
      - Royalty statements (Box 72, Folder 88)
  - Published Articles
    - List of writings and the amounts paid for them; list of paintings collected and disposed of by MLT, 1871-1910 (Box 72, Folder 89)
    - List of articles by MLT, 1883-1893 (Box 72, Folder 90)
    - List of calls to be made, 1879-1888 (Box 72, Folder 90)
    - "The National Deaf Mute College," Illustrated Christian Weekly, 1881 November 26
      - Early draft (Box 72, Folder 91)
      - Printed (Box 72, Folder 92)
      - Correspondence (Box 72, Folder 93)
    - "Five June Days in Ireland," Amherst Record, 1886 April 7, 14
      - AMS (Box 72, Folder 94)
      - Photocopy (Box 72, Folder 95)
    - "Children's Books-IV", 1886 December 16 (Box 72, Folder 96)
    - "With the Eclipse Expedition to Japan," The Nation
      - AMS, 1887 September 1 (Box 72, Folder 97)
      - Printed, 1887 September 22 (Box 72, Folder 98)
    - "The Ascent of Fuji-San," The Nation, 1887 October 13 (Box 72, Folder 99)
    - "In September," The York Evening Post, 1888 September 19, October 9 (Box 72, Folder 100)
    - "The Sexton's Story," Illustrated Christian Weekly, correspondence and printed copy, 1888 December 1 (Box 72, Folder 101)
    - "Ten Weeks in Japan," St. Nicholas, correspondence and printed copy, 1888 December (Box 72, Folder 102)
    - Book review of Madame Chrysantheme, The Nation, printed copy, 1889 January 24 (Box 72, Folder 103)
    - "Notes," The Nation, 1889 February 14 (Box 72, Folder 104)
    - Book review, "Recent Novels," The Nation, 1889 February 14, June 6 (Box 72, Folder 105-106)
    - "The Sexton's Story," Amherst Record, 1889 August 14, 21 (Box 72, Folder 107)
    - "A Quaint Old Japanese Town," Leslie's Popular Monthly, correspondence and printed copy, 1889 September (Box 72, Folder 108)
    - Note on an American Eclipse Expedition to West Africa, The Nation, 1889 October 24 (Box 72, Folder 109)
    - "Angola and the Eclipse," Christian Union, 1889 October 31 (Box 72, Folder 110)
    - Notes on the coming eclipse, The Nation, 1889 December 5 (Box 72, Folder 111)
    - Book review: "Children's Books-IV," The Nation, 1889 December 12 (Box 72, Folder 112)
    - Note on exhibit of U.S. Signal Service at Paris Exposition, The Nation, 1889 December 26 (Box 72, Folder 113)
    - Note on a meeting of the Royal Meteorological Society, The Nation, 1890 January 9 (Box 72, Folder 114)
    - Note on an American Eclipse Expedition, The Nation, 1890 January 9 (Box 72, Folder 115)
    - "The Total Solar Eclipse," Home Magazine, 1890 January 28 (Box 72, Folder 116)
    - "A Well-Filled Chimney," St. Nicholas, 1890 January (Box 72, Folder 117)
    - "The December Eclipse," Home Magazine, 1890 January (Box 72, Folder 118)
    - Book review, "Recent Novels," The Nation, 1890 February 6 (Box 72, Folder 119)
    - Note on Royal Meteorological Society, The Nation, 1890 February 13 (Box 72, Folder 120)
    - Note on Harvard Observatory Report, The Nation, 1890 February 27 (Box 72, Folder 121)
    - "Bright Bits From Bright Books," The Home Magazine, 1890 February-1891 February (Box 72, Folder 122)
    - "Notes," The Nation, 1890 March 6 (Box 72, Folder 123)
    - Review of "Dean's Daughter" and notes on temperature, The Nation, 1890 June 19 (Box 72, Folder 124)
    - Note on Maurice's article on the Battle of Waterloo, The Nation, 1890 August 21 (Box 72, Folder 125)
    - Notes on "Fossil Blizzards," The Nation, 1890 August 28 (Box 72, Folder 126)
    - "The Witch of Winnacunnett," New England Magazine, 1891 January (Box 72, Folder 127)
    - "An Ascent of Fuji the Peerless," The Century Magazine, 1892 August (Box 73, Folder 128)
    - Note on thunderstorms and rain, The Nation, 1892 September 1 (Box 73, Folder 129)
    - Note on Blyth's temperature observations, The Nation, 1892 December 29 (Box 73, Folder 130)
    - Note on the April 12, 1893 eclipse, The Nation, 1893 June 13 (Box 73, Folder 131)
    - "Acts of Vandalism," Amherst Record, 1893 August 23 (Box 73, Folder 132)
    - "In Memoriam," Amherst Record, 1893 August 30 (Box 73, Folder 133)
    - "Pike's Peak and Colorado Springs," The Nation, 1893 October 5 (Box 73, Folder 134)
    - "Automatic Eclipse Photography," The Photographic Times, 1893 October 13 (Box 73, Folder 135)
    - "Thoughts for Arbor Day," Amherst Record, 1894 April 25 (Box 73, Folder 136)
    - "Second Biennial of the General Federation of Women's Clubs," Amherst Record, 1894 May 30 (Box 73, Folder 137)
    - "A Half Century of Eclipses," McClure's Magazine, 1894 May (Box 73, Folder 138)
    - "A Famous Blind Pianist," Amherst Record, 1894 August 1 (Box 73, Folder 139)
    - "A Musical Treat," Amherst Record, 1894 September 19 (Box 73, Folder 140)
    - "Astronomical Notes," The Nation, 1895 January 24, January 31, March 21 (Box 73, Folder 141)
    - "From My Window," Springfield Sunday Union, 1895 May (Box 73, Folder 142)
    - "Emily Dickinson's Letters," The Bachelor of Arts, 1895 May (Box 73, Folder 143)
    - "Civics," The New Cycle, 1895 May 23 (Box 73, Folder 144)
    - Notes, book reviews, The Letter, 1895 Jun, Aug, Sep, Dec, 1896 March (Box 73, Folder 145)
    - "Astronomical Notes," The Nation, 1895 August (Box 73, Folder 146)
    - Note on lightning rods, The Nation, 1895 September 26 (Box 73, Folder 147)
    - "Astronomical Notes," The Nation, 1895 October 3, 24 (Box 73, Folder 148)
    - "Meteorological Notes," The Nation, 1895 November 21, 28 (Box 73, Folder 149)
    - "Amherst Electric Cars," Amherst Record, 1895 November 27 (Box 73, Folder 150)
    - Note on an eclipse expedition, The Nation, 1895 December 5 (Box 73, Folder 151)
    - Note on astronomy, The Nation, 1896 January 2 (Box 73, Folder 152)
    - "The Royal Family of Stars," The Letter, 1896 January (Box 73, Folder 153)
    - "Some Aspects of College Professors," The Bachelor of Arts, 1896 February (Box 73, Folder 154)
    - "The Spirit of Club Federation," The Letter, 1896 February (Box 73, Folder 155)
    - "The Next Total Eclipse of the Sun," The Letter, 1896 February (Box 73, Folder 156)
    - "Last Days in Hawaii," Chicago Times-Herald, 1896 June 9 (Box 73, Folder 157)
    - "The Amherst Eclipse Expedition to Japan," The Nation, 1896 June 18 (Box 73, Folder 158)
    - Letters on the eclipse, New York Sun: Correspondence, 1896 Jul, September (Box 73, Folder 159)
    - "Amherst Eclipse Expedition-II," The Nation, 1896 July 30 (Box 73, Folder 160)
    - Letter from Esashi, Japan, New York Evening Post, 1896 August 10 (Box 73, Folder 161)
    - "A Mid-Pacific College," Outlook, 1896 August 15 (Box 73, Folder 162)
    - "The Amherst Eclipse Expedition in Japan-III," The Nation, 1896 September 24 (Box 73, Folder 163)
    - "Amherst Eclipse Expedition-IV," The Nation, 1896 October 8 (Box 73, Folder 164)
    - "In Ainu Land With The Amherst Eclipse Expedition," The Outlook, 1896 October 10 (Box 73, Folder 165)
    - "Japan Revisited,", "Eclipses of the Sun," Brooklyn Daily Eagle, 1897 May (Box 73, Folder 166)
    - "A Great Modern Observatory," The Century, 1897 June (Box 73, Folder 167-168)
    - "The Cormorant Fishing at Gifu," The Independent, 1897 September 30 (Box 73, Folder 169)
    - "In Quest of a Shadow: An Astronomical Experience in Japan," The Atlantic Monthly, 1897 September (Box 73, Folder 170)
    - "The Eclipse in India," The Independent, 1898 January 20 (Box 73, Folder 171)
    - Evening Post, 1898 January 28 (Box 73, Folder 172)
    - "Singing Verses for Children," The Republican, 1898 February 9 (Box 73, Folder 173)
    - "Women in Hawaii," The Club Woman, 1898 March (Box 73, Folder 174)
    - "In Aino-Land," The Century, 1898 July (Box 73, Folder 175)
    - "A School Dedication in Northern Yezo," Journal of Education, 1898 September 22 (Box 73, Folder 176)
    - "A Poi Luncheon," The Independent, 1898 October 20 (Box 73, Folder 177)
    - "Life in Honolulu," Self Culture Magazine, 1898 October (Box 73, Folder 178)
    - Note on Mary Anton, New York Evening Post, 1899 March 31 (Box 73, Folder 179)
    - "The Great Red Planet in the West," St. Nicholas, 1899 June (Box 73, Folder 180)
    - "The Passing of the Grandmother," The Club Woman, 1899 July (Box 73, Folder 181)
    - "The Illiteracy of Forgetting Names," The Club Woman, 1899 September (Box 73, Folder 182)
    - "Angola and the Eclipse," The Christian Union, 1899 October 31 (Box 73, Folder 183)
    - Book review, "Outside of Things," Amherst Record, 1899 December 6 (Box 73, Folder 184)
    - "A Great Modern Observatory," The Century, 1890 (Box 73, Folder 185)
    - "Star and Gardens," Home Magazine
      - Serialized story, [1899?] (Box 73, Folder 186)
      - Drafts, 1899 November-1901 September (Box 74, Folder 187-190)
    - "The Coming Total Eclipse," The Club Woman, 1900 May (Box 74, Folder 191)
    - "Enroute to an Eclipse Station," The Nation, 1900 June 14 (Box 74, Folder 192)
    - "The Eclipse in Tripoli," The Nation, 1900 June 21 (Box 74, Folder 193)
    - "The Paris Exposition-IV," The Nation, 1900 July 19 (Box 74, Folder 194)
    - "The Passion Play of 1900," The Nation, 1900 July 26 (Box 74, Folder 195)
    - "The Passing Season," The Club Woman, 1900 September (Box 74, Folder 196)
    - "The Amherst Eclipse Expedition in the Orient," The Nation, 1901 March 25 (Box 74, Folder 197)
    - "From the Far East," The Amherst Record, 1901 April 17 (Box 74, Folder 198)
    - "The Eclipse of May 18th," The Singapore Free Press, 1901 April 29 (Box 74, Folder 199)
    - "Sights and Tastes in Tripoli," Boston Cooking School Magazine, 1901 April-May (Box 74, Folder 200)
    - "The Longest Eclipse Ever Observed," The Straits Times, 1901 May 18 (Box 74, Folder 201)
    - "The Amherst Eclipse Expedition," The Nation, 1901 May 30 (Box 74, Folder 202)
    - "Between Days on the Suez Canal," New York Evening Post, 1901 June 5 (Box 74, Folder 203)
    - "An Eclipse at Singkep," The Straits Times, 1901 June 8 (Box 74, Folder 204)
    - "The Amherst Eclipse Expedition-II," The Nation, 1901 June 13 (Box 74, Folder 205)
    - "Into the Path of Lunar Shadow," New York Evening Post, 1901 June 15 (Box 74, Folder 206)
    - "The Amherst Eclipse Expedition-III," The Nation, 1901 June 27 (Box 74, Folder 207)
    - "On the Eve of the Eclipse," New York Evening Post, 1901 June 30 (Box 74, Folder 208)
    - "The Amherst Eclipse Expedition-IV," The Nation, 1901 July 11 (Box 74, Folder 209)
    - "Final Plans for Eclipse Day," New York Evening Post, 1901 July 13, July 20 (Box 74, Folder 210-211)
    - Letter to the New York Evening Post, The Republican, 1901 July 23 (Box 74, Folder 212)
    - "Impressions of Siam," The Nation, 1901 August 8 (Box 74, Folder 213)
    - "The Venice of the Far East," New York Evening Post, 1901 August 10 (Box 74, Folder 214)
    - "Sounding the Ocean of Air," The Nation, 1901 September 5 (Box 74, Folder 215)
    - Letter from the U.S. Lawton in the Philippines: The News and The Woman's Journal, 1901 September 14 (Box 74, Folder 216)
    - "Civilization and Barbarism in Luzon," The Nation, 1901 September 19 (Box 74, Folder 217)
    - Letter from Manila, New York Evening Post, 1901 September 21 (Box 74, Folder 218)
    - "A Philippine Excursion," The Nation, 1901 September 26 (Box 74, Folder 219)
    - "In Panay and Samar," New York Evening Post, 1901 September 28 (Box 74, Folder 220)
    - "The Recent Eclipse," The Club Woman, 1901 September (Box 74, Folder 221)
    - "Around the World," The Holiday, 1901 October 2 (Box 74, Folder 222)
    - "A Circumnavigation Story," The Club Woman, 1901 October (Box 74, Folder 223)
    - "Mrs. Marsh's New Musical Game," The Amherst Record, 1901 December 4 (Box 74, Folder 224)
    - "An Equatorial Chinese Wedding," Boston Cooking School Magazine, 1902 June-July (Box 74, Folder 225)
    - "Mary Mattoon and her Hero of the Revolution," Amherst Record, 1902 November 19 (Box 74, Folder 226)
    - A Better Part, 1902 (Box 74, Folder 227)
    - "Everyday Japan," Boston Cooking School Magazine, 1903 January (Box 75, Folder 228)
    - "A Negrito Wedding at Mariveles," The Youth's Companion, 1903 June 25 (Box 75, Folder 229)
    - "A Better Part," Home Magazine, serial, 1902-1903 (Box 75, Folder 230)
    - Note on the astronomer Frank McLean, The Nation, 1904 March 2 (Box 75, Folder 231)
    - "The Village Problem," Federation Bulletin, 1904 April (Box 75, Folder 232)
    - "Polly in Japan", The Home Magazine
      - Serialized story, 1904 March-November (Box 75, Folder 233-234)
      - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 75, Folder 235)
    - "The Louisiana Purchase Expedition," The Nation, 1904 June 30 (Box 75, Folder 236)
    - "The December Lit," Amherst Student, 1904 December 17 (Box 75, Folder 237)
    - Note on Manila, The Nation, 1905 February 2 (Box 75, Folder 238)
    - "From Desert to Jungle in Search of Eclipses," Harper's Weekly: correspondence, 1905 April (Box 75, Folder 239)
    - Note on Eclipse Expedition, The Nation, 1905 July 27 (Box 75, Folder 240)
    - "Observing an Eclipse of the Sun," Harper's
      - AMS and printed, 1905 August 12 (Box 75, Folder 241)
      - Correspondence, payment, 1905 August 12 (Box 75, Folder 242)
    - "The Coming Eclipse," Boston Transcript, 1905 August 12 (Box 75, Folder 243)
    - "The Eclipse in Tripoli," The Nation, 1905 September 21 (Box 75, Folder 244)
    - "The Recent Eclipse Viewed in Tripoli," New York Evening Post, 1905 September 23 (Box 75, Folder 245)
    - "From Tripoli to Tunis," The Nation, 1905 October 26 (Box 75, Folder 246)
    - "Five Little Japanese Girls of Long Ago," Woman's Journal, 1905 December 2 (Box 75, Folder 247)
    - "Observing the Eclipse," Optical Journal, 1905 December 28 (Box 75, Folder 248)
    - "Witchcraft in New England"
      - Address in Springfield Homestead: correspondence, 1906 January 13 (Box 75, Folder 249)
      - Connecticut Valley Historical Society: notes and draft, AMS, 1906 (Box 75, Folder 250)
      - Notes and draft TMS, 1906 (Box 75, Folder 251)
      - Printed copy, 1906 (Box 75, Folder 252)
    - "In the Moon's Shadow," Harper's Weekly, 1906 January 27 (Box 75, Folder 253)
    - Note on pilot chart of N. Atlantic, The Nation, 1906 April 20 (Box 75, Folder 254)
    - Book review, Historic Hadley, The Nation, 1907 January 31 (Box 75, Folder 255)
    - Notes on astronomy and meteorology, The Nation, 1907 February 7, 28, March 7 (Box 75, Folder 256)
    - "The Unappreciated Crow," Country Life in America, 1907 April (Box 75, Folder 257)
    - Notes on New Bedford fishing and astronomy in Antwerp, The Nation, 1907 May 30, June 6 (Box 75, Folder 258)
    - Letter from the Andes, The Springfield Republican, 1907 August 21 (Box 75, Folder 259)
    - "Observing an Annular Eclipse," The Nation, 1907 August 22 (Box 75, Folder 260)
    - "Photographing the 'Canals' on Mars"
      - New York Post: printed, 1907 August (Box 75, Folder 261)
      - The Nation: printed and AMS, 1907 September 19 (Box 75, Folder 262)
    - "The Canals on Mars," Evening Standard, 1907 October 14 (Box 75, Folder 263)
    - "Our Ruddy Neighbor Planet," The Independent, 1908 April 9 (Box 75, Folder 264)
    - "Chasing Eclipses," Harper's Weekly, 1908 August 1 (Box 75, Folder 265)
    - Letters: "The New Yacht Aloha," Springfield Republican, 1910 March 29 (Box 75, Folder 266)
    - Note on Blue Hill Observatory, The Nation, 1910 August 4 (Box 75, Folder 267)
    - "Pachacamac," Bulletin of the Pan American Union
      - AMS, correspondence, 1910 December (Box 75, Folder 268)
      - Printed, 1910 December (Box 75, Folder 269)
    - "Tripoli and Her People," Springfield Republican, 1911 October 8 (Box 75, Folder 270-271)
    - Note on the astronomer Williamina P. Fleming, The Nation, 1911 November 2 (Box 76, Folder 272)
    - Note on artificial heating and its effects on climate, The Nation, 1911 December 14 (Box 76, Folder 273)
    - "Astronomy," American Year Book
      - AMS, 1910 (Box 76, Folder 274)
      - Galley proofs, correspondence, 1911 (Box 76, Folder 275)
    - "Mysterious Tripoli," The Argonaut, 1912 June 29 (Box 76, Folder 276)
    - Note on Blue Hill Observatory, The Nation, 1912 August 15 (Box 76, Folder 277)
    - Letter: "Singing at Mount Holyoke," Springfield Republican, 1912 October 7 (Box 76, Folder 278)
    - Note on total eclipse, The Nation, 1913 March 13 (Box 76, Folder 279)
    - "A Touch With Livingstone," Amherst Graduate Quarterly, 1913 April (Box 76, Folder 280)
    - Note on the Milky Way, The Nation, 1913 May 1 (Box 76, Folder 281)
    - Book review, The Ways of the Planets, The Nation, 1913 June 12 (Box 76, Folder 282)
    - "In the Land of No Twilight: Singkep," Travel, 1913 September (Box 76, Folder 283)
    - Note on Connecticut Valley Historical Society, The Nation, 1913 (Box 76, Folder 284)
    - "Memorials of a Great Astronomer," The Dial, 1915 November 25 (Box 76, Folder 285)
    - "Witchcraft in New England", 1916 (Box 76, Folder 286)
    - "The Amherst Historical Society," Amherst Graduates Quarterly, 1918 May (Box 76, Folder 287)
    - Letter to the editor: "Kilavea in Action," The Nation, 1919 March 29 (Box 76, Folder 288)
    - Biographies for Biographical History of Massachusetts, 1916-1919 (Box 76, Folder 289)
    - "Of Pines," Miami Herald, 1921 December 27 (Box 76, Folder 290)
    - "In the Shadow of the Moon," Miami Tribune, 1925 January 18 (Box 76, Folder 291)
    - "Total Eclipse of the Sun," Coconut Grove Times, 1925 January 22 (Box 76, Folder 292)
    - "Early Memories of Mrs. E.D.E.N. Southworth," Bulletin of the National League of American Pen Women, 1928 November (Box 76, Folder 293)
    - "Emily Dickinson's Literary Debut," Harper's Magazine, 1930 March (Box 76, Folder 294)
    - "The Literary Debut of Emily Dickinson", Harper's Magazine
      - Early drafts, 1930 March (Box 76, Folder 295)
      - Second draft, 1930 March (Box 76, Folder 296)
    - Book review, The Life and Mind of Emily Dickinson, Saturday Review of Literature, 1930 September 6 (Box 76, Folder 297)
    - "The Thoreau Family Two Generations Ago", privately printed for the Thoreau Society, 1930s (Box 76, Folder 298)
    - Editorial notes by Millicent Todd Bingham on Mabel Todd's Nation articles, Undated (Box 76, Folder 299)
  - Unpublished Writings
    - Poem, "Millicent", [early 1880s?] (Box 77, Folder 300)
    - "Franz Schubert," AMS, 1881 November 10 (Box 77, Folder 301)
    - "Flower Painting in Oil Colors"
      - First MS draft, 1881 (Box 77, Folder 302)
      - Second MS draft, 1881 (Box 77, Folder 303)
      - Correspondence, 1881 (Box 77, Folder 304)
    - "Autumnal" or "Falling Leaves," AMS, 1886 October 8 (Box 77, Folder 305)
    - Emily Dickinson Poet and Woman, drafts, [post-1886] (Box 77, Folder 306)
    - "Stars and Mountains," AMS and printed, 1888 (Box 77, Folder 307)
    - "Beginning of Home Magazine Story," AMS, 1888 (Box 77, Folder 308)